Risa!
Bye!
See you later.
Come in.
Oh, Sis!
Brought you some clean clothes.
How’s your leg, Riku?
It doesn’t hurt too badly,
as long as I don’t move it too much.
Sheesh...
Try to be careful.
Well, what about your leg?
Are you still running?
You shouldn’t be worrying
about others right now.
Got it...
Oh, that’s right. You know about
the Wind Festival in Fura City?
Yeah, I do.
It’s a pretty big event, right?
Yeah.
So, I wanted to ask you something...
I’m home...
“Catch a Pokémon”?!
No way! No way! No way!
Please, I’m begging you!
I don’t wanna!
Why would I do that?!
I mean, look at my leg!
What if I forced myself to go
and ended up collapsing?
I’d just be lying there, unnoticed by those around me,
thinking about you as I died a pitiful death...
You’re heartless! Why was I cursed
with such a cruel sister?!
Oh, fine! You just want me
to go there, right?
Yay!
I’m not asking you to do it
for nothing, of course.
Here, take this.
What is it?
To show my gratitude.
Wear those to the festival.
They’re adorable!
You really do have your moments!
A Pokémon, huh...?
An award ceremony will be held to give the winner of
the Pokémon Catching Contest a trophy.
Got it.
Father!
Good morning, Largo.
Are you going
to the Wind Festival today?
Yeah!
Take care of yourself.
You, too!
All right!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
This young man is
Satoshi from Masara Town.
Together with his partner, Pikachu,
he continues his journey to become a Pokémon Master.
He now finds himself in the city that
lives in harmony with the wind, Fura City.
The Wind Festival is
currently being held here.
Looks fun!
Pikachu!
There’s a bunch of
even better stuff over here!
It looks really fluffy and delicious!
Huh... Didn’t think it’d be this festive.
Well, I suppose this isn’t half bad.
Stay away from me!
I swear, I can’t even
look at the flowers in peace...
What?!
I-I can’t! I mean... It’s tomorrow!
That’s... That’s just... But...
Are you okay?
Oh, yes, I’m fine...
Please don’t touch...
Um... Is there really
no way you could...?
I see...
Lily, are you hurt?
I’m fine!
You should be more careful.
But it’s all so much fun!
Well, then...
I’ll take you somewhere
even more fun!
We’re gonna play all day!
Hooray! Uncle, you’re the best!
PokéRan Channel!
Everyone, it’s time
for PokéRan Channel!
Today is the start of the annual
Wind Festival held in Fura City!
“Oh, how I wanted to go!”
To all you poor kids thinking that,
I’m right there with you!
Here on this channel, I’ll be giving you
the latest news on the Wind Festival!
They say the Wind Festival originates
from a promise made with Lugia.
Apparently, this was once a barren land!
But the people and Pokémon
lived by supporting one another!
In honor of this bond,
Lugia promised to bring the wind to this land!
The people used this wind
to develop the city!
And now, Lugia stops by once a year!
After seeing the bond between
people and Pokémon for itself,
Lugia sends a blessed wind
upon this land, each and every year!
And there’s another thing
you should know about this city!
There was a large wildfire in the past,
and Lugia was the one who put it out!
Uncle!
We bought ice cream!
Here, this one’s for you.
Oh, thanks, Lily!
Say, say, can I see your Pokémon?
Do you have
a super strong Pokémon?
Oh, of course I do!
Look.
What kind of Pokémon is it?
It’s the strongest Pokémon!
Let me see!
No!
Oh, I mean, now’s not a good time...
It’s exhausted after a crazy battle
I had the other day.
Lily, look!
You’re about to drop your ice cream!
Oh, no!
Thank you, big brother.
She was completely set on
coming to the Wind Festival.
Don’t mention it.
But is Lily... doing okay?
Yeah, she’s been
quite healthy these days.
Say, say, Uncle,
what’s that Pokémon called?
Oh, that’s
the Legendary Pokémon, Lugia.
This city became big thanks to it.
Wow! Uncle, you know so much!
It’s a tale from a time long gone by...
It happened on a cold day.
My work had brought me to this city.
And then...
I saw a red light shining
in the distant mountains!
I realized, it must be a wildfire!
I shouted,
“The fire’s getting closer to the city!
“Everyone, get outta here!”
I called out to Lugia,
and prayed for it to save us.
Then Lugia answered my prayers
and put out the fire!
And thus, the city was saved!
And everyone lived
happily ever after.
I’m so sorry...
Uncle, you’re the best!
Yay!
Oh, come on...
You and your lies...
I wasn’t lying.
It was just... creative liberties.
Come on, Lily.
Where do you wanna go next?
That place over there looks fun!
Yeah, let’s go!
If only I could speak in front of people
the way he does, too...
Lemonade! Lemonade!
Would you like some lemonade?
Gomazo!
Hold on!
What’s this thing’s problem?!
Keep it away from me!
S-Sorry...
Didn’t you know?
That old lady’s
a known Pokémon-hater!
What? Really?
Hey, don’t let go!
Did you see her hands?
She’s wearing gloves! In the summer!
Ow...
Largo!
I’m sorry!
That’s the mayor’s daughter,
you know!
Look what you’ve done!
We can’t make any more
lemonade now, you know!
I-I’m sorry...
But I have somewhere I need to—
Shut it!
Pay us back!
Don’t fight.
It’s a festival, after all!
You should be nice to each other!
Wh-Who’re you supposed to be?!
Get ‘em! Gomazo, Rollout!
Dodge!
What?!
Amazing...
Use Iron Tail!
Gomazo, use Tackle!
He’s asking if you wanna keep going!
W-We’ll let you off the hook
for today, you know!
C’mon, we’re leaving!
We’ll get you for this!
Thank you!
Don’t mention it. Are you okay?
Yup! Thanks to you, too, Pikachu!
I’m Satoshi from Masara Town.
This is my partner, Pikachu.
My name is Largo.
Did you come here for the Wind Festival?
Yup. That’s right.
Quite impressive.
Yeah! He handled that like a pro!
What’ll we do for our next
Pikachu capture plan, meow?
I’ve made up my mind...
We’ll start selling juice, too!
Time to put our skills to the test...
Well, then let’s not waste time and...
...Sell juice?
There’s lots of people around.
We could cause a big juice boom
and really rake in the cash!
F-Fair point,
but what about Pikachu?
What do you think, Nyarth?
We should get right to work, meow!
Sohnansu!
That’s right!
Does that mean
we’ll get to meet Lugia?
Yup. On the last day of the festival.
It’s the Wind Festival’s main event!
That’s awesome!
Ah! Look!
That’s the Sacred Flame!
Lugia uses it as a marker
to send the wind to us.
I see... So what’s that?
The old power plant.
From what I hear, it was damaged in the wildfire
fifty years ago and isn’t being used anymore.
But back during that fire,
Lugia made the rain fall
and saved everyone!
Lugia’s awesome!
Well, I’m going this way.
The Wind Festival venue is over there.
Got it. Thank you!
Later!
See ya!
All right!
Oh, thank you all so much!
Congratulations! Here’s your prize.
Thank you!
Here you go, Lily.
Yay! Thank you, Uncle!
Oh, it was a piece of cake!
How nice!
Since you won it for me,
I’ll cherish it forever and ever!
Are you okay?
Yeah... I’m sorry.
I am so sorry! Are you hurt?
No, I’m fine.
It’s my fault for
not paying attention.
Where’s your Pokémon, lady?
Oh, this?
I actually came to this city
to catch one,
but it must be mega rare!
I can’t find it anywhere!
You should ask Uncle, then!
Huh?!
He’s an amazing Pokémon Trainer!
Really?
Well, please tell me, then!
Um... What Pokémon do you want?
This one.
Oh, that?
Yeah, that one’s mega rare, all right.
What? Really?
Where can I find it?
Well, you know...
Oh, right!
There! It’s over there!
I got info saying it’s
on that mountain!
Really? Thank you so much, Mister!
Sure...
Now you’ve done it, Pikachu!
The Wind Festival’s annual Catching Contest
will begin shortly on Main Street.
All Pokémon Trainers,
please feel free to participate.
Did you hear that, Pikachu?
Did you hear that, Uncle?
The Catching Contest! You should enter!
Uh?!
I’m sure you can win!
Sure! Leave it to Uncle!
I’m a great Pokémon Trainer, after all!
I’ll beat all those other tough guys and
give you the victory trophy as a present!
Really? Yay!
Oh, come on...
The presenter isn’t coming?!
What are you gonna do, Torito?
I-I’ll fix it, somehow...
“Somehow” isn’t good enough!
The presentation is tomorrow.
How can you find someone on such short notice?
You should put a bit more faith in u—
I-It’s fine!
I’ll work it out on my own...
Somehow...
This is our chance to let the world
know about our research.
I’m sure you, too, know how important
this presentation is.
Please.
Win, huh...
What’s that?
It says it’s
the Pokémon research pavilion!
Pokémon research, is it?
No, you got it wrong!
Are there any doctors around here?
Oh, yes. I’m here.
Has the heat finally cooked my brain?
N-No, you’re quite sane.
I’m so sorry!
Are your clothes all right?
Yes...
But don’t just pop
out of nowhere like that!
Are you trying to kill me?!
Oh, no, not at all...
Here. I need you to sign this.
Hand it over to the Executive Committee.
Oh... Of course!
I swear...
I’m very sorry, Miss.
Hey, you!
You a Pokémon researcher?
That means you know a lot
about Pokémon, right?
You two get this.
Eat up.
I’m sorry you were hurt
because of me.
If you eat these Oran Berries,
you’ll get better faster. So eat all of it.
I’ll be back later.
Whoa...
Look at all these people!
You can do it, Uncle!
I wonder what kind of
Pokémon we’ll find!
Isn’t this cool, Pikachu?
Lum Berry juice!
Perfect for the Catching Contest!
Would you like some Lum Berry juice?
Lum Berries are
very healthy for Pokémon!
Paralysis, sleep, confusion...
We’ve made juice out of these super special berries
that can cure any condition, meow!
It’s finally time for
the Wind Festival’s annual Catching Contest!
The rules are simple:
Marked Pokémon are spread throughout
the streets of Fura City, waiting for the participants!
But they’re all tough Pokémon
who won’t just let themselves be caught!
This will be no easy task!
All contestants, please use the exclusive balls
we’ve provided for you to catch these Pokémon!
You’ll be given points based on
the level of the Pokémon you catch!
Whoever claims the most points
before time runs out will be the winner!
Testing, testing...
Can you hear me? Over.
Yes, I can hear you just fine.
Mr. Kagachi, you will help me with the presentation
if I help you here, won’t you?
Duh. It’s a win-win for both of us.
So don’t let me down, Doctor.
Got it.
Oh, and please don’t push
my Hitodeman too hard.
Of course!
Well then, let’s get to it!
Ready...
Get!
Let’s go, Pikachu!
Let’s get ourselves some awesome Pokémon!
We’re gonna win this!
It’s an Arbo!
Lightning Speed!
Go!
All right! That’s the first one!
It’s so tough!
The participants keep on
catching Pokémon!
The one performing the best so far...
...is Competitor Kagachi!
Go, Uncle!
He’s making superb use of Hitodeman’s ability,
Luminescence, which causes Pokémon to approach it!
Pikachu, did you see that?
Right! Let’s chase it!
This is rough...
It’s going perfectly!
You’re in first place right now!
This is hopeless...
What is that thing doing?
Uso! Uso Uso!
Lies!/You’re kidding me!
Mr. Kagachi, Usokki is
weak against Water!
This is your chance!
Oh, my! I just received word that
Banguirus is rampaging through the city,
and that Competitor Satoshi
is in pursuit of it!
Um... It appears that Banguirus’s neck
became entangled in wires!
No way...
Banguirus!
Pikachu, can you
lead Banguirus over there?
I’m counting on you, partner!
You shouldn’t lie
to yourself so much.
It’ll become a habit.
Mimicry is what Usokki is known for.
Can it!
Tell me where the next
Pokémon is, already.
Now I’ve got you, Banguirus!
This is bad! There’s a large crowd
in front of Banguirus!
They’re in trouble!
Pikachu, it’s all on you now!
Use Iron Tail!
Banguirus!
Yeah, don’t worry.
You’re safe now.
Well done, Pikachu!
Spectacular! Competitor Satoshi
has saved Banguirus!
A friendship that transcends catching Pokémon!
It’s burning hot!
Can you stand?
The second place winner, and the man who
saved Banguirus, Competitor Satoshi...
...gets the Mayor’s Prize.
Thank you very much!
I’m the one who should be thanking you,
for saving Banguirus.
I had Pikachu with me,
so I thought I could do it!
It’s all thanks to him!
And the winner of the contest...
...is Competitor Kagachi!
I did it, Lily!
Uncle, you’re so cool!
Congratulations on coming first
in the Catching Contest!
Thank you!
It was no big deal for
someone as great as me!
Incidentally, are there any Pokémon
you’d like to get next?
Huh? Oh, um...
I understand there’s supposed to be
a super rare Pokémon around here...
What? Is that so?
A super rare Pokémon?
Since I’m here at the Wind Festival
anyway, I’d love to get it.
Did you know?
I wanna get it!
No...
I wonder what kind of Pokémon
it could be!
That was our winner,
Competitor Kagachi, everyone!
Thanks a bunch!
PokéRan Channel!
We just got some juicy info!
It seems a super rare Pokémon
can be found in Fura City!
No Pokémon Trainer can let
this chance pass them by, can they?!
Was I hearing things?
I wanna keep playing with Uncle...
She’s sleep-talking.
She’s been running around all day.
She must have had fun.
That’s the most important thing.
Anyway...
Why are you following me around?
Don’t you “Usso” me!
I gave back all
the Pokémon I caught earlier!
Heck, I didn’t even
catch you in the first place!
What? You followed my brother
because you like him?
Leave me alone!
What do I care what somebody
like you thinks of me?
Were you even listening to me?
How was the Wind Festival?
Yup! It was really fun!
I rode the roller coaster,
went to the haunted house...
What about you?
It was a lot of work today, too.
That man who won the Catching Contest said
there’s a rare Pokémon in this city...
He must have been joking!
I’ve never heard of anything like that.
Um... What about the one
from the stories... Zeraora?
Largo, that Pokémon
doesn’t exist anymore.
But...
We mustn’t scare the citizens.
So don’t say anything strange.
All right...
Sheesh... Where is that thing?
Don’t scare me like that!
Ow...
You there!
This mountain is off-limits!
Don’t you know about
Zeraora’s Curse?
H-Hang on...
Zeraora? Curse?
Are you a tourist?
In any case, you can’t be on this mountain!
Now, come with us.
I-I get it, but just
tell me something first...
This Pokémon is
supposed to be super rare...
Do you know it?
Super rare?
That’s just an ordinary Eevee.
They don’t live on this mountain.
That old geezer lied to me!
What’s with you?!
Where’d you come from?!
Don’t you dare touch this!
Stay away from me!
Well done, Hitodeman.
Thanks to you,
I should be fine tomorrow.
He was an excellent public speaker.
I’m sure he’ll do well.
Nyarth, what’s that guy researching?
Hmmm...
Looks like it’s Pokémon
abilities and moves, meow.
That’s great!
I don’t really get it,
but I’m sure it’ll be useful!
Well then,
let’s go grab it right away!
Yeah!
I-Is somebody there?
Hold on, everyone...
Oh, is this what made the noise?
Everyone, watch out for
shards of glass.
This is the chemical
made from Doble ink.
Did it slide off the table?
That was close!
I panicked...
We’ll try again tomorrow, meow...
There might be a Pokémon we know nothing about
somewhere in this city, Pikachu!
Oh, that’s right. I slept outside
because of those things.
What are we gonna do today,
Pikachu?
I found you!
What the...?!
Pikachu says he’s sorry.
Don’t worry about it.
I’m just happy to be getting help from
the runner-up in the Catching Contest!
It’s really not that big a deal.
On the flipside,
the winner fed me a bunch of lies!
Shhh!
Great work, Pikachu.
That’s the one!
If you wanna catch it,
you gotta battle it first!
Risa, where’s your Pokémon?
Uh? Don’t have one...
Oh...
Right! Pikachu, can you help her?
Okay, and now...
We’re jumping right in!
What? You’re kidding!
Oh, no!
I’m sorry, Pikachu!
Calm down!
Listen up!
Keep a close eye on Eevee!
Right, got it.
Pikachu, dodge!
Risa! Use Lightning Speed!
Lightning Speed!
Now! Throw the Monster Ball!
Right, got it.
Go!
So close!
One more time!
Okay!
Use Iron Tail!
Iron Tail!
Use 100,000 Volts!
100,000 Volts!
Risa!
Okay!
Please!
You did it, Risa!
Huh? You mean I got it?
Yeah!
I did it! I did it! I got Eevee!
Thank you, Satoshi, Pikachu!
Wh-Where are your eyebrows?!
I’m back.
Hey, you should let Eevee out!
Sure.
I’m Risa. Let’s be friends.
Don’t worry.
It’ll warm up to you before long.
That was the first time I’ve ever
caught a Pokémon. It was so exciting!
It was, like, how can I put it...
I haven’t been so fired up
about anything in ages!
Yeah. It’s nice, isn’t it?
Ever since I was little,
I’ve been focused on running track,
so I never even learned
how to catch Pokémon!
So you’re fast, then?
Yup! I might not look it,
but I’m the regional champion!
Awesome!
But I...
...gave it up.
Huh? Why?
I got injured.
It’s long since healed up, but...
Suddenly,
the thought of running scared me.
I think with Eevee by your side,
you’ll be able to run again.
Huh? Why?
I mean...
I kinda feel like, even if there are things
we can’t do on our own,
anything’s possible if we’ve
got Pokémon with us.
That’s so cheesy!
Ms. Junsa?
Has there been a crime?
Hey, Doctor.
Wh-What brings you here
so early in the morning?
What’s the meaning of this?
“This”...
You mean the Pokémon?
They’ve been strangely clingy
ever since I went here yesterday.
Oh... The chemical that spilled yesterday
was based off the Pokémon move Sweet Scent.
It’s a move that emits a scent that Pokémon like,
which causes them to gather...
Why would you even make
such a lousy drug?!
I don’t want anything to do
with Pokémon!
Hurry up and fix this!
B-But that’s... I need time...
Torito!
Bad news!
I just got word from
the festival administration...
Anomalies in the electrical system
for several attractions,
laundry detergent
covering the streets,
and all kinds of other pranks
have been reported.
Who could have done this?
Hey, you!
Because of you
I spent the whole night—
I know! Just say something random.
I’m with my niece.
Help me save face here!
Please!
Huh?
I’m begging you!
Huh?!
When you die,
it is not going to be pretty.
Lady, you got the Pokémon!
Sure did!
And it’s all thanks to your uncle!
Excuse me, everybody.
We will make an announcement
once the festival is ready to be reopened.
Please be patient for just a bit longer.
That’s all they can do, I guess...
Should we just pass some time
back at the hotel?
Mayor, we’ll help out, too!
Oh, Satoshi!
Largo.
Oh, you two knew each other already?
We met in town yesterday.
Hey, when you said “We,”
you were including me, too, weren’t you?
Well, we all want this fixed
so we can get back to the Wind Festival, right?
Let’s help them, too, Uncle!
Eh?!
I would be happy to receive help from
the Catching Contest top two!
Well, actually, I have business to attend to
over at the science presentation...
The science presentation? Why?
Well, you see...
That’s just another one
of your lies, isn’t it?
Poor girl...
I won’t tell anyone about that thing earlier,
so you better help us here!
Oh, fine!
All right! Let’s do this!
Now there’s another one...
Here you go.
Doctor, didn’t you have
a presentation today?
That’s right.
It’s time for the PokéRan Channel!
The second day of the Wind Festival
is off to a turbulent start!
Someone’s been playing pranks,
preventing them from starting up for the day,
but it looks like the festival committee and the citizens
are hard at work getting everything back in order,
so there’s no need to worry!
Sheesh...
Why do we have to help out?
It’s probably just
Zeraora’s Curse, you know...
You guys!
Gah!
Hey, what’s this
“Zeraora’s Curse” thing?
You haven’t heard?
Zeraora, who died in the fire fifty years ago,
put a curse on the mountain, you know!
If people set even one foot on the mountain,
disaster will befall them!
That’s Zeraora’s Curse!
No!
That’s not true!
Wh-What’s gotten into you?
This is a message from
the Wind Festival administration.
We have verified that
everything is secure,
so the Wind Festival is reopened
as of this moment.
Great to hear!
It really didn’t take that long
when we all worked together!
We did it!
There’s been an emergency...
Let’s hurry and finish up the rest, too!
What a relief...
Let’s hurry and get ready.
All right!
Doctor, another one showed up...
You’d better hurry and do something,
before I’m buried in Pokémon.
I-I’m very sorry...
I’ll find a solution
before you’re buried.
As soon as
the presentation is over...
I’m counting on it.
The cable cars are
running again, too!
That’s case closed.
Huh? Where’s Uncle?
He’s acting really suspicious.
Maybe he’s the one
who pulled the pranks?
He’s not!
Well, let’s follow him!
He’s not coming...
Torito, we’re running out of time.
O-Okay...
This is the footage for
the presentation.
Got it.
Are you all right?
I-I’ll manage, one way or...
He’s hopeless.
Move! Move! Move!
So...
Um... Well...
Hang in there!
Th-Thank you all for... for...
Man up! You are a man, aren’t you?!
...for coming here, um...
What’s wrong?
Stage fright?
Oh, no! I’m too late!
Mr. Kagachi!
Big brother,
what do you need here?
Oh, well...
Torito, the footage!
You...
You don’t have any
new members this time, do you?
Mr. Kagachi, if you catch that one,
you’ll be in first place.
Water Gun will work best on it.
Gotcha. Use Water Gun!
There!
Right!
Now I won’t have to disappoint Lily.
My niece believes that
I’m an amazing trainer.
Big brother, what was that?
Umm... Well...
Uncle... Isn’t that...?
Oh, th-this is...
Did you... lie?
Who are you people?!
If you ask us “Who are you people?!”...
We’ll answer out of
sympathy for the world!
No, this is no time to
be answering, meow!
That said...
We’re leaving!
Uncle...
I hate you!
Lily, wait!
Lily!
Are you okay, Lily?
Thieves! They’re getting away!
Team Rocket?
Let’s get ‘em, Pikachu!
Eevee! Eevee!
Eevee!
Oh, no! What do I do?
Eevee, hang in there!
Eevee!
Let me see.
Can you help it?
I can. There’s no need to worry.
Lucky, use Healing Pulse.
Eevee...
Hang in there, Eevee...
Hold it, Team Rocket!
Stinking brat boy!
Give it up already!
Pikachu, use 100,000 Volts!
Do your thing, Sohnansu!
Eevee!
It’s fine now.
Good thing we were able
to treat it quickly.
Its leg is still slightly hurt,
but it will be fine if you let it rest.
Thank you so much.
How is Lily?
They just had a doctor
take a look at her.
Her body’s always been weak...
Looks like the fatigue from
the past few days caught up with her.
I’m sorry. It’s my fault.
Nah, it’s my fault for
lying all the time.
How did it go?
I’m sorry. I lost them.
Eevee’s injured?!
Yeah... After you left,
I lost it in the crowd...
But I just had Ms. Joy take a look.
It’s all right.
I see.
That lousy Team Rocket!
What they took was a chemical
made from Spores.
Does Ms. Junsa know?
Yes, I told her.
It looks like they’ll continue searching.
Everybody must be tired.
Let’s go home and rest.
How’s Lily?
She’s asleep.
I’m planning on
taking her home tomorrow.
Sorry...
Where are you going?
I...
...don’t deserve to show my face
around Lily anymore.
I betrayed her.
You’re such a fool...
Don’t follow me...
Just leave me alone!
It’s not like you’re
my Pokémon or anything.
You’re throwing what I told you
right back in my face... and I deserve it.
I’m done lying.
There’s no point in you following me.
Go wherever you want.
How many times do I have to tell you
to stop following me?
I’m done with that stuff.
Never again...
I’d rather be on my own than...
If only I’d have run back then...
Could I have protected you?
I see. Well done.
Father?
Largo.
What’ll happen to
the Wind Festival tomorrow?
We just agreed that it’ll proceed.
We should be able to meet safety requirements
by strengthening security.
Oh. That’s good!
Don’t worry, just sleep.
We’ll have to
summon Lugia tomorrow.
Sure. Good night.
Good night.
Cheers!
Now, bring it out!
Wait... You mean
you weren’t holding it?
Huh? I mean, I handed it off
to Nyarth, didn’t I?
Wha? I didn’t get it, meow!
Sure I handed it to you!
I said “Nyarth!” and
passed it behind me.
I was running in front of you
the whole time, meow!
Then, that means...
Huh? Then who did I pass it to?
Freaky!
Oh, no way! Is it, like,
a Ghost-type kinda situation?!
What’s going on?
I’ve never seen this before!
Risa?
Hey... There’s a lot of noise outside.
What’s going on?
Satoshi, look!
The windmills are...
I heard the wind’s weakened...
...because the Sacred Flame disappeared.
Disappeared? The whole thing?
Yeah.
Then... We’ve got bigger problems
than the Wind Festival, no?
The Sacred Flame?
Let’s go!
Sheesh...
Why do we have to do this?
Whose fault do they think it is
that the presentation failed?
We hear you.
We never should have had him
work on the presentation in the first place.
You should’ve said that
before we started!
Enough.
Torito cares more about Pokémon
than anybody else here.
Is there anybody else here who
loves Pokémon as much as him?
Who knows as much
about Pokémon as him?
Anyone?
I believe that he has what’s most important
for a Pokémon researcher to have.
More so than any of us.
The wind’s stopped...
What’s going on?
Lily, are you doing all right?
Where’s Uncle?
He said he was going home
ahead of us.
I...
...was so mean to him.
Lily.
“It’ll be fine! Cheer up!”
“It didn’t bother Uncle one bit!”
Mayor!
Satoshi.
Is it true that
the Sacred Flame’s gone?
It is.
And that’s why the wind’s...
Lugia uses the Flame as a marker
to send the wind to us.
But now...
Lugia doesn’t know where
to send the wind?
Correct.
If the Sacred Flame isn’t found by the end of the final day,
which is to say, by sunrise tomorrow...
The city’s power reserves
will eventually run dry.
Oh, no...
Can I take a closer look?
Very well.
You know, I’m really
not good with heights!
What’s up, Pikachu?
You’ve figured something out, huh?
We’re going back down?!
Good! This one’s real feisty!
All of these Pokémon oughta
fetch a high price!
Pokémon living in good health,
out in the untouched nature...
Talk about a rewarding hunt!
U-Umm... Pikachu?
Pikachu!
You mean the one that
stole the Sacred Flame...
...was Doble?
The Sacred Flame?
It’s been stolen.
Pikachu followed the scent
from the pedestal to here...
And found Doble.
Doble’s scent...
Could it be Doble’s ink?
Perhaps...
I thought it just slipped and
fell down back then...
Could someone have
knocked it down?
I can’t be sure, but if it was...
Doble uses ink to mark its territory.
I wanted to use it for marking,
but distilling it made it turn transparent.
But I can use this flashlight to...
Bingo.
Amazing!
Pikachu, it’s all thanks to you!
If we follow these tracks,
they should lead us to the thief.
Let’s get going!
I hope they’ve canceled it now...
Don’t worry. This time, I’ll protect you.
Didn’t think there’d be
a place like this in Fura City.
Let’s start looking for
rare Pokémon already!
People will come here in droves
after seeing that broadcast!
Yeah.
Those people are here for Zeraora?
Oh?
What brings you guys here?
You from Fura City, little girl?
You haven’t seen any rare Pokémon
around here, have you?
I sure have!
Really?
Where?
That way!
It’s like nothing I’ve ever seen!
Thank you, little girl!
Oh, you’re quite welcome!
What’s that?
A Himeguma and a Metamon, huh?
No!
Y-You’d better hurry,
or the rare Pokémon will get away!
Do you want that?
We’ll be taking those, too.
Come out, Hellgar!
Let’s go, Nyula!
Hellgar! Flamethrower!
Nyula! Icy Wind!
No, Zeraora! You have to hide!
Hey, hey!
I’ve never seen this one before!
There’s the rare Pokémon!
Fire Fang!
Slash!
Zeraora! You mustn’t push yourself!
You’re still injured!
It’s really fast.
But it looks like it’s hurt.
Yeah. Don’t let this chance get away!
Ice Shard!
Keep putting pressure on it!
Hellgar, use Flamethrower!
Zeraora!
Zeraora, hang in there!
Zeraora, they’ll catch you!
Now, let’s finish this.
What?!
Are you okay, Largo?
You did good by yourself!
Satoshi...
Father... Everybody...
I am the mayor of Fura City.
Choose your next move wisely,
or I’ll take legal action!
This ain’t good...
We’d better leave.
Yeah.
Hey!
Don’t go after them.
We have other things to worry about.
Father, it’s not Zeraora’s fault.
I was the one who did it.
That’s Zeraora?
That’s right.
But the stories say it died.
And yet, it’s lying right in front of us.
This is it, right?
Do you understand how
much trouble you’ve caused?
Largo?
I first met Zeraora a little while back...
I was playing with the Pokémon
at the foot of the mountain.
But then a rock fell...
It could have crushed us all, easily...
But Zeraora protected
me and the Pokémon.
But it got hurt in the process...
It was my fault.
So I thought I had to look after it.
Everyone in the city
is scared of Zeraora...
I thought that I, alone, had to be on its side,
and look after it until its wounds healed.
But there was that man who knew
there was a rare Pokémon here...
I knew that it was only a matter of time
before everyone came to try and capture Zeraora.
So I thought they might leave
if the Wind Festival was canceled...
I knew there’d be trouble
if I took the Sacred Flame...
But once the festival was canceled,
I was going to put it back! I swear!
I’m sorry! I’m so sorry!
Largo...
Largo.
You did well protecting Zeraora.
There’s something I must tell you.
The truth about Zeraora.
Zeraora has been living here
for a very long time.
It was the lord of this land,
and had the respect of the Pokémon.
They lived together in peace.
As for us humans...
We cut down the forest where those Pokémon lived,
seeking a rich life for ourselves.
But that was what caused...
...the wildfire fifty years ago.
Oh, no...
The forest turned into a sea of fire...
The people didn’t have time to
concern themselves with the wild Pokémon.
They were all panicking.
But Zeraora refused to abandon
the Pokémon that had been left behind.
Zeraora has held a deep grudge
against humans ever since.
That’s why it was so...
But the people continued to
lose Zeraora’s trust.
All Zeraora wanted was to
live in the forest with the Pokémon,
but trainers came in droves,
hoping to catch it.
The mayor at the time
wanted to make amends,
so he decided to lie to the city.
“Zeraora is dead. It has cursed the mountain, so setting foot on it is strictly forbidden.”
That was the only thing
we could do to protect Zeraora.
I never knew...
There aren’t many who
know the truth.
Especially not the younger people.
This is the truth about Zeraora.
What was that?!
Smoke?
Some sort of Wind Festival event?
No...
Hey, that looks pretty bad,
doesn’t it?!
It’s headed this way!
What is that?!
Oh, no... It can’t be...
Do you know something?
Ah, wait!
The color of that smoke...
These symptoms...
This may be
the Spores chemical.
The one that Team Rocket stole?!
Yes...
Lucky, please use Aromatherapy.
What do you mean,
“Spores chemical”?
It was still in the testing stage...
The capsule contained a highly concentrated chemical
with the properties of the Pokémon ability Spores.
And that’s related to these Pokémon?
If you inhale the Spores,
you’ll suffer poison and paralysis.
That’s what that smoke does?
Why would you even make that?
While researching, I found that
it can be used to treat human illnesses.
It’s me.
Mayor, reporting in...
A smoke of unknown origin has sprung forth,
and a fourth of Fura City has been covered in it.
It’s continuing to spread as we speak.
We’ve confirmed that it’s a toxic substance
that paralyzes anyone who inhales it.
We’ve issued an emergency evacuation order
for those in the affected areas.
There is no time to waste.
Please, come back at once!
Understood.
Father...
This is my fault...
Let’s do this! Just watching
won’t do anyone any good!
Let’s protect Fura City, together!
What?
Well, what are we supposed
to do against that?
We’ve got Pokémon!
You’re with me, yeah?
We can’t do everything on our own,
but with Pokémon,
we can do anything!
Courage and strength just spring out
when we’re with our Pokémon!
That’s Pokémon Power!
Pokémon Power? That’s so cheesy!
Pokémon Power, is it?
I suppose you’re right.
Let’s give it a try!
Now you’re talking!
Doctor, is there any way
to get rid of that smoke?
Eh?!
Umm, if I go back to my laboratory...
...and mass-produce a chemical based off
the Pokémon ability Natural Recovery...
Oh, it won’t work! I can’t spread that
throughout the entire city!
What if we use the wind?
The wind?
We have the old power plant.
I see.
But isn’t it broken down?
No, Ms. Hisui can make it work!
What do you mean?
I made that power plant.
Wow! I never would have guessed!
The propellers can be faced
in different directions.
If we spin them in reverse,
we should be able to make the wind blow.
But there’s probably only
a fifty-fifty chance that it will run.
Fifty-fifty?
Okay! Let’s do it!
You all help, too, will you?
This’ll require some physical labor.
Well then, Doctor, Ms. Hisui,
you head for the old power plant.
I’ll go with Risa and Largo...
...to give aid to Zeraora and the Pokémon in the forest,
and bring them somewhere safe!
Yes!
The smoke is denser than air,
so the mountaintops should be the safest place.
And take this. A Potion.
Please use it on the Pokémon.
Thank you!
Well then, good luck, everyone!
Calm down!
Please, evacuate in an orderly fashion!
Mia! Where are you?
Is Lily okay?!
Yes, we’re fine.
We’re riding the aerial lift right now.
But it seems like it’s made an emergency stop.
It’s not moving.
Uncle, hel—
Hey, Lily! Mia!
Can I even help them?
I mean...
I’m completely worthless...
Didn’t I tell you to leave me alone?
What’s your problem?!
What do you think we could do?
We’d just get there,
make up some lie and run away...
You and me, a pair of weaklings...
Ow! Hey, what’s your deal?!
Knock it off!
You...
Usokki...
You’ll... help me?
Thank you, Usokki.
I take back what I said
about being done lying.
I’ll lie as much as it takes,
if that means I can
protect what’s dear to me!
We’re unbeatable!
Together, we’ll save Lily and Mia!
Hey!
Wh-Why didn’t you tell me sooner?!
Status?
Sir. More than half the city is
already covered in smoke.
We’ve asked the Pokémon Center to provide shelter,
but there’s just not enough room for everybody.
Mayor, how will we fight this?
With Pokémon Power.
Torito!
Where did you go? We’ve been given orders
to use this place as a shelter, too.
Um... Well...
Help us move these
research materials, will you?
What’s wrong?
Torito, are you listening to me?
Oh, you see...
Pokémon Power... Pokémon Power...
Pokémon Power...
Hurry up, Torito! There’s no time to—
Just listen to me!
I know that you all hate me.
I’m always fidgeting,
and I can barely even talk to people.
I’m sure you all think
I’m a huge weirdo.
But just for now,
please lend me a hand!
There’s still a way to save the city!
I don’t want to run... I want to save
the people and Pokémon with my research!
Torito.
What?!
You always do this.
Putting other people and Pokémon’s
needs before your own...
This time is no different.
I deeply respect you as a scientist.
What?
What do you need me to do?
I want to help.
Me, too! Let’s do this!
Give us your orders!
What should we do?
Everyone...
I want to mass-produce
a Natural Recovery chemical!
All right, everyone,
let’s get to work!
There it is! We got it now!
Where is it hiding?
Come out, Zeraora!
Don’t let it get away! Catch it!
That should do it.
Oh, you’re awake, Zeraora!
Don’t worry. Those people are gone.
Wait, Largo!
It’s all right, Zeraora!
We haven’t done anything!
I brought it. Where’s the doctor?
He’s not here yet.
Hey! How do we clear out that smoke?!
Oh, it’s you!
Granny?
We intend to counteract the poison
using the old power plant.
Lily’s in trouble! So let’s get moving!
To that old plant or whatever...
What was that?
That came from the transformer.
The smoke may have
caused it to short circuit.
Granny!
The power’s going out...
Hurry! Hurry, meow!
Why does this always happen?!
Get in here! Quick!
We made it...
Are we safe?
It’s a blackout!
Wait, you can’t! Not now!
We were so close!
What’s wrong, Lucky?
Granny, are you okay?!
Prepare a bed for her!
Understood!
Don’t! I’ll manage.
We can’t wait for the doctor.
Let’s just go.
It’ll take a while to get
the old girl running.
Right, got it! I’ll take you there!
First this smoke came
out of nowhere,
and now there’s been an explosion
at the transformer, causing a wildfire!
Here you go.
Thank you...
Now it seems that Fura City’s lost its power
and is covered in darkness!
To everyone in Fura City,
take care of yourselves!
Zeraora!
Don’t tell me it’s...
Zeraora must have gone
to help the other Pokémon.
Hey!
Risa!
I’ll follow Largo.
You put that thing back  in place
and summon Lugia!
What?! Hey, wait a second!
You can get it there faster
than anyone else here.
No, you’re the only one who can!
I know you can do it!
It’s all on you!
There’s no way!
I mean...
I...
...can’t run...
Eevee?!
Why are you trying so hard?!
I mean...
I kinda feel like, even if there are things
we can’t do on our own,
anything’s possible if we’ve
got Pokémon with us.
Together...
We can do anything if we’ve got
Pokémon with us...?
You’re giving it your all.
So who am I to just give up?
Now it’s my turn.
Let’s put the Sacred Flame back,
together!
All right...
Come here.
Hang on.
This is our Pokémon Power!
Think! Think! Think!
I’ve got the knowledge...
I just have to make the gears turn in my head!
I have to brainstorm harder
than anyone ever has!
Lum Berries? That’s it!
Excuse me!
This is it! This could work!
Will you let me have these?
I need them to save the city!
What?!
Hang in there for
just a little more, Lily...
I’m okay...
I know Uncle will save us.
I get it. So we gotta get
the propeller running?
Then if we throw
the doctor’s chemical into it...
That about covers it.
Well, that’s not good...
We’ll just have to
find another route.
Huh? No, but...
That’s the old power plant right there, isn’t it?
It’s right in front of us!
We’ll put out the fire and go on!
No! I won’t allow that
under any circumstances!
What’s wrong, Granny?
If only...
If only I could have reached
a little further...
Bullu! Come back!
Bullu!
Come here! Hurry!
Don’t leave me!
Snap out of it, Granny!
I don’t know what you’ve been through,
but we’re here for you now!
Thank you, Bullu...
My beloved partner...
...must have protected the key
for this moment!
Now it’s my turn.
Will you help me?
Let’s show them this
Pokémon Power thing!
Can you help from the sky, too?
Right! I’m not sure what just happened,
but the path is clear!
What do I do...
I’ll never get there if I have to keep
avoiding the Spores...
Sis!
Riku?!
I’ll navigate for you.
Huh?!
I’m looking for the best route to avoid the smoke
and get to the Sacred Flame pedestal!
Found it!
How did you do that?
Actually, how do you even
know where I am?
Just focus on the run!
Right!
Get into the forest in front of you!
It should slow down the Spores a little!
Got it!
Zeraora!
I thought so!
Watch out!
I’m fine!
You hate humans, don’t you?
You can’t trust us, can you?
That’s such a sad way to live.
In that case...
Let’s be friends!
I’m fine.
You bonehead!
Pikachu! 100,000 Volts!
Pikachu! Iron Tail!
Use Lightning Speed!
It’s done!
We did it! It’s finally ready!
Torito! The mayor’s sent
a car to pick you up!
Got it!
Mayor!
Everything’s ready.
Good.
This is countermeasure HQ.
We’ve asked you all to seek shelter due to Fura City
falling under an outbreak of spore smoke.
If there are any people or
Pokémon that need help,
we ask that any people nearby
do whatever they can to assist.
Furthermore, we have just dispatched
a countermeasure team to work on resolving the situation.
They are doing everything in their power
to ensure your safety as soon as possible.
Now, the rest of what I want to say is
my own request as your mayor.
In addition to the spore smoke outbreak,
a wildfire is spreading.
In the event that
the countermeasure team succeeds,
I would ask that you all
help me put out the fire as best you can.
This city has been living a lie
for too long.
This time, we ourselves,
along with the Pokémon fighting beside us...
...ought to stand up
to those flames!
This is crazy...
How on earth are we supposed to
make this massive thing move without electricity?
With this.
Good girl...
Okay, seriously?
From here on, this will be a battle of endurance!
I’ll need you all to do your part!
You gotta push
that thing together! Got it?
Hey... You mean we gotta
use brute force, Granny?!
What else do you suggest we use?
Seriously?
Now quit dawdling and
get into position!
Here we go!
All together now...
Heave... Ho!
Heave, ho!
Well, then...
Here we go!
Pikachu, are you okay?
Zeraora, please stop!
You understand, don’t you?
Not all humans are bad!
Please, believe in us!
Zeraora!
Oh, no!
Pikachu...
Good, everyone’s safe.
Come on!
We were worried about you!
Zeraora?
All right!
We’re friends now!
I’m sorry I kept you waiting!
It’s finished!
Wait... Mr. Kagachi?
Yo, Doctor!
Have a look!
I got this thing into place!
You must be joking!
It’s half true.
Incredible...
This can work!
I know it can!
Now we just have to make sure
this hits the propellers...
Got it. Give it to me!
I’ll toss it.
H-Hold on!
You mean you’ll throw it
into that thing?!
Aren’t there any ladders to...
They’re all gone.
Burned up in the fire.
Oh, no...
We’ve got no time, Doctor.
This is the only way.
I don’t believe this!
You all gotta give it
one more push!
Now it’s time to
spin the propeller!
Mr. Kagachi.
This is all the chemical we have,
which my team and I put our all into producing.
Yeah, I know.
I swear I’ll get this done, for Lily!
Now, give it all you’ve got!
Well, this doesn’t look good...
All the debris is gonna
throw the bottle off course.
You got an idea?
Got it!
I trust you, partner!
Time for one last push!
Spin!
All right!
Spin! Spin!
Does this mean...?
It worked!
Give me a report on how the citizens
and Pokémon are doing, stat!
Of course!
What a great feeling!
You did it, Torito!
C’mon, look outside!
They did it!
Hey, did ya see that, Doctor?!
I did! Amazing!
You did it on the first try!
You’re a natural!
I couldn’t have done it
without Usokki!
Don’t celebrate just yet!
This isn’t over!
The flames aren’t dying down...
Don’t worry! We just have to keep them in check
until Risa summons Lugia!
Those are...
Half of you, circle around
to the other side!
Father?!
Largo!
It’s Zeraora!
I’ve never seen it before!
It’s okay, Zeraora!
This time, they’re trying to
protect the forest!
Everyone, put out the fires!
Satoshi!
Everybody!
This is looking dire.
Get the sprinklers running!
They should work,
long as the system hasn’t broken down!
I’ll go ask the Electric-type
Pokémon for help!
Let’s put an end to this!
All right! We’ll help, too!
Zeraora, it’s true that there are
bad people among us, like those hunters...
And we do the wrong thing
sometimes, too. I get that.
But I want you to know
that not all of us are bad.
Satoshi said...
...that we humans may be
weak on our own,
but that we’re so much stronger
with Pokémon by our side.
I wonder, doesn’t that
work both ways?
I think it would be nice if
Pokémon felt the same way.
I’m counting on you!
Give it your all, guys!
All right... Please, work!
You did it!
Satoshi!
Hang in there!
You can do it!
I know you can!
Zeraora!
Zeraora...
I think it would be nice if
Pokémon felt the same way.
Just a little more...
Almost there!
Go!
You’re so close!
You can do it!
I believe in you, Zeraora!
Zeraora!
No!
Zeraora, hang in there!
Thank goodness!
Lugia?
Lugia, make the rain fall!
We need you to
put out the fire! Please!
Lugia...
Whoa... I got to see it, for real!
Risa got the Sacred Flame
back in time!
The Sacred Flame?
She ran all the way to the pedestal?
Yeah! I told her Lugia
was sure to come!
You gotta admire that girl’s guts!
Zeraora and Lugia
saved the city once again.
No, it was us this time!
Every last one of us!
Everyone...
The only reason we were able to
redo the final day of the Wind Festival...
...was because we had the help of
every person and Pokémon here.
During the crisis,
a young boy told me...
...that what we can’t do alone,
we can do with the help of Pokémon.
Our citizens, Pokémon, and everyone else
who helped put out the fire...
...proved this to be true.
I wish to make this a great city
in which we can live in harmony with Pokémon.
In order to make that happen,
I hereby abolish the law concealing Zeraora’s existence.
Moving forward, we will
coexist with Zeraora!
This planet is filled with
strange, strange creatures.
In the skies, in the seas,
in the forests, in the cities...
You can find them
all over the world.
We humans and these creatures play together,
help each other out,
work together, live together...
Though sometimes, we may fight...
We live in harmony with them,
forming many different kinds of bonds.
For every last one of these creatures,
there’s another dream, another adventure waiting!
And they are known as
Pocket Monsters, or for short...
Pokémon!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Movie
Our Story
The charts are filled with positive words
positive na kotoba de afureteiru hit chart
Pushing at you more than you care for
tanonde mo nai no ni yatara senaka o osu
You're working hard enough already
kimi wa mou juubun ganbatte iru no dakedo
When suddenly you're rushed,
shiranai ma ni sekasareteru
pressed to change
nanika kaero to semarare
What's wrong with the status quo?
ima no mama ja dame kai?
Is the future gonna leave
mirai wa hayaashi de nakya
if you don't run for it?
tadoritsukenai mon kai?
Even your negativity's an important part of you
negative datte kimi no daiji na kakera
on your grand journey
soudai na tabi no tochuu sa
Stay as you are, be true to yourself
ari no mama kimi no mama de iin janai
Your pure voice can echo far
kakko tsukezu ni koe ni sureba hibiite yuku
And if you don't let the lyrics
kiita koto aru you na meigen ni
be swapped out for some catchy quotes
shiranai aida ni surikawaranai uchi ni
and it's no hit, well,
meikyoku ni wa naranakute mo
it's still your song
tatta hitotsu no your song
If the wind blows against you, just turn around
mukaikaze wa ushiro mukeba oikaze ni naru
Trust the future to be
shisen muketa hougaku ni wa
wherever you look
ashita ga aru to shinjiru
Go at your pace
kibun shidai de yukou
The future will be there,
mirai wa tada soko ni atte
waiting for you
kimi no koto matteru
It won't impose upon you,
komuzukashii jouken tsuketari wa shinai
nor will it carry you
mukae ni mo konai kedo
If some dreams are hard to explain
kantan ni katarun ja nai yume o
Let them laugh if they don't try to understand
wakarou to shinai tanin ga hora waratte iru
If it's hard to stack up hits now
kantan ni kasanerun ja nai kimi o
The charts have their trends and fads, don't worry
sugu ni kawatte yuku hit chart ni nanka
Just as you are,
kimi wa kimi no mama de zutto
you can make it so far, far away
ikun dakara far away
Shogakukan 12 magazines art contest
Winners
Corocoro Ichiban!
Yamazaki Reon - Fukushima Prefecture
Monthly Corocoro Comics
Fujiwara Mio - Shiga Prefecture
Corocoro Aniki
Higashi Shouko - Ooita Prefecture
Pucchigumi
Tamura Honomi - Tokyo Metropolitan Area
Shougaku Ichinensei
Shimizu Sana - Gunma Prefecture
Youchien
Yoshida Atsurou - Aichi Prefecture
Kids have the time to take the long way round
shounen ni wa toomawari suru jikan ga ataerare
TV-Kun
Kinjou Mitsuki - Osaka Prefecture
Age brings the wisdom of knowing the shortcuts
roujin ni wa chikamichi o shiru chie ga sazukerarete
Pokémon Fan
Tanaka Miki - Hokkaido
Weekly Shounen Sunday
Kouki Kuroda - Kanagawa Prefecture
So don't laugh and don't get jealous
dochira ka o warau koto nakare urayamu koto nakare
Chao
Komatsu Kokona - Tokyo Metropolitan area
Both ways are right,
sorezore no michi ga aru
Shogakukan Kids
Koike Miku - Saitama Prefecture
and your road is yours alone
dare mo kimi no michi wa yukenai
Sunday Web Every x pixiv
Wataame - Tokyo Metropolitan Area
It takes notes and rests to make a melody
melody wa onpu to kyuufu ga tsukuru
Nobody can sing a song without pauses to breathe
breath no dekinai uta wa dare mo utai ya shinai
Just like how sunny days need rainy days,
hareta hi mo ame no hi mo aru you ni
how every day has a morning and night,
asa to yoru ga kyou mo megutteku you ni
and how travelers repeat
deai to sayonara kurikaesu
their endless meetings and farewells
tabibito no you ni
And so, Fura City has now
established a nature preserve!
Sis?!
Riku, tell me how you knew
where I was and what was going on!
And I want the truth!
Well, those things are
really high-tech, you see...
I kinda wanted footage of
the Wind Festival... you know?
Pikachu...
What kind of Pokémon
are we gonna meet next?